OVUYOVWE COURAGE ENDURANCE

Akako Street, Ile-epo Bus Stop, Odo ona, Ibadan, Oyo State <u>courageovuyovwe99@gmail.com</u> +2348166298591

PROFILE

An experienced, enthusiatic and focused teacher who is committed to promoting the education and well being of students at all times. Very passionate about the teaching field and able to establish a supportive relationship with not only students but also their parents and fellow teachers with the aim of promoting and reinforcing a student's independence and self esteem. I always engage in continuous learning and research in order to broaden my knowledge and I am committed to innovation and good practices.

PERSONAL DATA

DATE OF BIRTH: 3rd Dec, 1992

SEX: Male

STATE OF ORIGIN: Delta

SKILLS

- Excellent knowledge of the subject to be taught
- Excellent communication skills
- Possess various teaching methods and techniques
- Excellent ability to create interest in subject among the students
- Planning, organisation and time management skills

EDUCATION

2012-2016: University of Port-Harcourt, Rivers State.

B.Sc. Animal and Environmental Biology Second Class Honours (Upper Division)

2004-2010: Niger College, Edo State

West African Secondary School Certificate

1999-2004: Ivbiore Primary School, Edo State

First School Leaving Certificate

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Novélle Centre Professional training company

2018: UKHSE-Level 1 (Award in Health and Safety at Work)

UKHSE-Level 2 (Risk Assessment Practical application)

UKHSE-Level 3 (Environmental Awareness)

Department of Petroleum Resources (Environmental Impact

Assessment)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2018 – 2019 St. Ann's International High School

Rumuibekwe Estate, Port Harcourt, Rivers State

Duties/Responsibilties

- Planned, prepared and delivered well structured lessons.
- Organized and supported a range of extra-curricular activities.
- Monitored learning through a range of assessment techniques.
- Developed strategies to manage classroom behaviour.

2017 -2018: National Youth Service Corps (NYSC)

St. Rita's Private School, Tunkus, Plateau State

Accomplishment

- Assisted in class assessment and presentation of term result leading to the improvement of students' performance
- Participated actively in decision making, planning and application of effective teaching techniques that increased the students' desire to learn and to fully understand what they were taught.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Sports: football

Hobbies: traveling and meeting people

REFEREES

Available on request